And I just,
I had some follow-up questions. Mainly,
Sure.
I wasn't there,
so I couldn't ask these questions.
And I wanted just a better understanding
of the audit solution that you guys used
today. So I was wondering if, first off,
you could...
Yeah.
Take us through maybe an inspection that
is completed and show us the different
pieces of what you've built in this tool.
Sure.
Yeah.
All right, yeah, let me share my screen.
All right, let's do that.
And just so here's an example.
This whole QSA, landscape quality audit,
irrigation inspection,
development maintenance handoff,
they're all kind of the same, right?
It's meant to timestamp to document the
status of the community property.
as we receive it and just kind of
digitizing the inspection transitions,
new spark, new starts or irrigation.
And I'll just walk through this since
it's up right now.
This is the development maintenance
handoff. It's got the property name,
the address, and all these are
touch buttons,
there's no typing or anything else.
Yeah.
You can, with this product,
you can actually speak into the device
Yes.
instead of typing Aperture Orlando,
just speak into it.
Ki.
The time and date turnover, you know,
all the all the different stats we need
to document.
Is there a primary turf warranty?
You know, what's the warranty length?
The install, who did that,
who owns it through the first year,
so the...
Hey, back to the speaking.
Are you speaking per box or can you like
speak out a narrative and then it fills
itself in?
So you can do both, right?
You can create a dropdown and have,
or you can create a dropdown with
predetermined answers.
You can you can do multi and have a
certain number of check boxes and it'll
all be highlighted.
It's really,
you can do whatever you want with it.
And that's the beauty of iAuditor.
It's made for safety inspections. And,
you know,
I really started doing this because I
realized that irrigation,
we're definitely not capturing all the
All the monies, all the time,
all the resources spent to take care of
our customer, at least in my eyes.
And I said,
getting our arms around this would be a
huge uplift to the business.
So, um, yeah, so all this stuff is,
it's either pre-populated or you speak
Okay.
into it. It's very good at picking.
And the property address, property name,
all of that,
that's all manual entry at first, right?
Is it connected to anything?
Here.
No, no, probably.
Property address is 1 button you hit
geolocate and it'll capture that.
Oh, okay.
So while you're on the property,
you initiate this.
Yeah, I'm doing it.
I'm doing it while I while I walk.
Okay.
So or I'll get to the meeting about 10 or
15 minutes early.
Yeah.
I'll make sure this is all done.
And to minimize the conversation,
I'll just take all the photos randomly.
And after the meeting,
I'll spend 15 minutes putting it in.
And this is this is the end result.
Right,
so you're gonna see the inspection
inspection notes concerning our issues.
All the things that popped up.
Okay.
And what's really nice,
which is different than what we have
today,
is this solution actually has the ability
to document video.
And the photos,
when I send this digitally,
the photos are able to zoom in, right?
We're not able to zoom in today with QSAs,
but this allows you to zoom in and really
see up close what's going on.
How about, how about like,
like your base irrigation system,
like the components of the system,
the location of those components?
Is that part of this audit thing or do
you maintain that separately?
Yeah.
Now, this is totally separate, right?
So here's the templates that I've been,
I've worked on for some time.
The drought conditions report,
that's what really started Victoria
Gardens. You know, we had a,
we were tasked as a branch manager in my
first three months.
I had a $100,
000 invoice come across my desk and my
VPGM says, hey, you got to pay this.
I'm like, $100,000 for what? He goes,
well, we've damaged some turf.
And after some research,
I realized that that's not completely
accurate. A lot of what we're being asked.
asked to replace was not in our court.
So I created this drought conditions
report. And what it does is, I mean,
I walk you through the inspection, right?
So it's.
Drop down, right?
Who's doing the inspections? What section?
And obviously with your phone,
it's a lot more intuitive too,
but so time and date, you know,
just whatever property address,
it'll geolocate it.
Then you get to the meat and potatoes.
But what's really nice with this report,
and it was just to notify, right?
It became a living,
breathing document that our customer
could access at any time.
and see all the reports.
So it kind of took a lot of pressure off
Okay.
of us by saying, hey,
remember I brought this up in that
meeting. We talked about it at this date.
It became,
you guys have access to the reports at
any time.
You have access to view and see all the
reports. If you got any questions,
we can meet and talk about it.
So...
And the big difference between a QSA and
this then is that they can access like a
live living thing anytime,
whereas the QSA is just a PDF output,
kind of static. Is that?
The different? Okay.
Right, yeah, so the QSA,
when you talk about QSA,
who's what QSA are you talking about?
You're talking about the Brightview QSA?
Yes.
Yes, yeah, so this one,
this one's actually living, breathing.
They have access, well,
we have access to it too,
but what's nice is it's always there,
right? To me,
I would have that document or an
irrigation inspection report living
inside.
Bright View Connect,
which is obviously would be part of FSM,
but almost like the QSAs that happens
where it's time and date stamped,
someone's like tapping their fingers.
We need to have something like that for
irrigation, man, because that really,
as you know, make or breaks the landscape.
You can do a lot of things well.
Put down the best fertilizer.
The crews are doing an amazing job mowing
and detailing, but if it's not...
If it's not green, it's, you know,
that's the first sign of a problem.
Yep, OK.
Okay, so the irrigation inspection,
this thing folded out into two parts,
right? So Kelsie called me, he goes, hey,
listen,
the board wants us to inspect this
property and we don't have the resources
or the wherewithal to be able to provide.
an inspection per house because that's
what they're requiring. Not a street,
not a once a month inspection.
They need to be able to 0 in on a house.
So, every every house has a clock.
No, every, every.
Okay.
Every st belongs to a zone.
Okay.
And each house, yeah, so each house might,
you know,
there might be 15 houses on each zone,
but...
Okay.
The key for the management is that
they're able to pull up at any time the
inspection report for Mrs.
Smith's house or Mrs. Johnson.
Okay.
So, that's why this whole thing,
the quarterly inspection, started.
Alright, so I'll walk you through that.
Again, geolocation,
home and street address,
that they talk into it,
time and date stamped, service technician,
site name, reason for the site visit,
drought conditions,
repair follow-up service requests.
wet checks quarterly, right?
So there's a couple key things that we
need to notate.
Are there visible hotspots,
visible line breaks, mainline washouts,
or visible overwatering?
Then you get into the next section,
a little bit more meats and potatoes,
controller numbers, zone number,
irrigation restrictions,
are they in effect?
Then you get into the details, right?
And so there's some logic behind all this,
but so inspection details,
this is going to be zone one, right?
So what did we do?
Um...
Edge were straightened, nozzles clean,
spray coverage confirmed,
spray pattern adjusted.
Right, so we do that.
That populates there.
Are there repairs needed? No. If it's yes,
logic pops out. What repairs are required?
Uh, let's say replace head. All right.
Click next.
And then are there some modifications to
recommend?
Yes, logic.
We're going to add a pop-up to increase
coverage.
Estimated cost, that's not an issue today.
And the zone details,
this is where they can actually just talk
into it.
And closing details,
these are pre-populated.
There are no other pending upgrades to
suggest.
There are no other pending repairs needed
at this time, right?
So, they go through this,
it spins through this,
and they complete the inspection.
On average, the guys are doing...
I don't know. I would say...
80 to 90 inspections per week.
in order for us to do the 1,
125 homes per quarter.
And what's really cool is...
is this.
So if I go to Victoria Garden Irrigation.
We send over to the customer on a weekly
basis just an overview.
Right, so this is an export.
It takes about 10 minutes max to kind of
format.
Because we're no longer doing the repairs.
Right, so,
so this is this is all the repairs
completed,
so it's got all the all the stuff that
you know we we pulled from.
When you said you were no longer doing
the repairs, what?
At.
Yeah, so what happened was,
so what's kind of cool is we started
doing the repairs and I mean,
our billing was incredible.
Let me just pull this thing up.
Uh, July irrigation repairs, yeah.
So,
I would pull the inspection report and
reformat it, and it would, you know,
within about 15 minutes,
it would populate.
The repair total.
Right in this column.
And for this month.
We did 8605 and it fluctuated between 8,
000, 12,000, 15,000.
And what's kind of cool is the irrigation
manager used absolutely no time doing
this. I mean, I did it. We can,
AI is pretty advanced now.
It could be automated.
if you wanted to.
Doesn't mean you don't need an irrigation
manager,
just means he can do other things.
But so what happened was over the time,
over four or five months,
the board decided to hire their own
irrigation tech because the repairs were
too expensive.
and they just hadn't budgeted for it.
So we got into a position where we still
needed to send out reports.
And that's the export that I showed you
guys that we sent out on a weekly basis.
So, they they pay you to inspect.
They pay us to do quarterly inspections,
yes.
Okay.
Yeah.
So what's nice is the customer has this
ability too because I added them as a
user.
They can actually go to the inspections,
add a filter.
Completion date.
Let's say, last seven days.
And all the inspections are right here.
They can view the report.
And this is my house address.
I just...
Yeah, by house address,
I just threw a basic template together.
Okay.
some basic formatting enough to look
presentable, right? So some would say,
oh man, that's kind of cool.
So here's a digitized inspection.
Here's the PDF.
Right here.
I hate that it comes out this way and
it's not formatted the way I like it.
Um...
But it's got the basic details,
the address, the home number,
time and date, who inspected it,
reason for inspections,
visual inspection notes,
and then basically the details.
So zone repairs completed.
Are there any recommendations? No,
we should know.
There are no other suggestions.
And you know what's kind of cool, guys,
is that the property manager of this $2
million job, she's like, Mike,
irrigation's A non-issue now.
The fact that you're doing this,
it's the community's gonna find something
Awesome.
else to complain about,
but this is phenomenal.
Um...
Yeah,
I want to know how to add this to my
other jobs for the other communities we
maintain.
And so I think getting in front of this,
offering something like this on a larger
scale would be very beneficial to
Brightview.
Okay.
And Michael,
you said the some that you can do this on
the phone, correct?
Yeah, yeah, you can do it on your phone.
And as a matter of fact,
the irrigation team, Makai,
it's actually one guy doing all these
inspections. You know,
at first he was a little bit disgruntled.
You know,
it's just something new and bringing him
in for training.
you know, over the course of,
I don't know, maybe 2 days,
just having conversations,
making sure it felt right to him,
that this is probably like the 5th
iteration of how the,
how it looks on his phone, the sequencing.
We just kind of refined it and he's like,
man, this thing's perfect. He loves it.
He loves it, like...
Yeah, but he does it on his phone.
I mean,
I could probably share my my phone and
walk you guys through it.
Let's see, share screen.
with audio, start broadcast.
All right, let's see.
Pull this thing up.
Ohh, let's see.
Probably should spell your name correctly.
Yeah, you know what?
These fat fingers, man, is like, ohh.
Let's see.
Okay, here we go.
Oh, man.
Yeah, I, I...
Let's see if this works.
Okay, so there's some stuff in progress.
All right, so here it is.
Irrigation inspection.
GPS.
12129 Regiment Drive.
You know what,
it's having trouble while I'm recording
or sharing and...
Speaking,
but that's something I would just talk
Right.
into time and date.
Okay, so you actually,
you touch inside the box and then use the
Yeah.
phone to go speech to text. Okay.
Yeah.
Yep, yep, just touch inside the box.
Visual hotspots, no.
Visual ladder line breaks, no.
No, and yeah, overwatering controller two.
Zone, zone 12.
No, no watering restrictions.
And then, yeah, the guys just go through,
tap it.
Are they do they have a master master
plan of the irrigation system so they
know where they are on the property and?
Do you guys have like some kind of
digital,
Yes, yes.
do you have digital mapping or is it a
PDF or what are you using?
And you went on mute.
He went back to your desktop.
Hey, guys.
Yep, lost you.
Hey, guys.
Yeah, can you hear me? Yes.
You there?
Hey, it's Trinidad. Can you hear me?
Yes.
Okay, perfect. Sorry about that. Yeah,
so there is a master plan, right?
One of the main things I sent the guys
out to do immediately was to break out
the...
the irrigation by timers,
and then the zones,
and kind of sync that up with the
irrigation department and also the
property manager.
So, I'm sorry, what is it again?
Is it like a PDF map or?
Yeah, it's a it's a map that we created.
It's a there's a PDF version somewhere
that irrigation put together.
And what it basically does is it outlines
the locations of all the master valves.
Or timers,
and the irrigation tech would just flow
through each of the each of the timers.
Okay.
Yeah.
Okay.
What I think you had mentioned on the
last year, I mean,
this is kind of minutiae,
but the overspray.
What is that?
When you talk about overspray,
are you talking about the system is
spraying on the concrete or on the houses
or roads, sidewalks?
Yeah, no, so the overwatering, right?
So there.
Overspray is overwatering.
No, that, so I don't,
I don't know what overspray you're
referring to.
Okay.
Yeah, but inside the inspection report,
one of the visual cues we did was visual
inspections of over water.
Okay.
Water consumption is such a hot topic.
that, you know, they need to identify,
there's a red flag that pops up and they
I gotcha.
look for over watering so they can go
directly to the resident and either find
them or have a conversation. So.
And I think, I mean,
most of my questions were answered in
your...
Demo,
I'm talking about internal versus
customer split.
When, okay,
so say that you're doing this with other
properties that don't have this yet,
or where you are doing repairs.
Mmh.
Were you taking this report? And then,
I mean, I guess you showed that to us.
Mhm.
You had a consolidated report that pulled
up.
you would hand that over.
Would you guys do extra work sales orders
for those to do the work and go through
our regular ancillary pipeline?
Yeah, that's exactly right. It would be.
Okay.
When it came time to invoice, it would,
we just grab the data from Extra Work and
plug it in so they can, you know,
approve it.
And are you guys using field service
management at all right now with
irrigation?
The mobile app technicians or do you know
I...
if any branches are?
I, I am not aware. I mean, I'm...
Definitely, we in Sanford,
there was an irrigation manager change
out.
So I'm not aware that FSM had bled into
irrigation.
So I wouldn't I wouldn't have asked.
I'm curious now,
but Andrew McCall is the irrigation
manager in Sanford.
So, I may may bend his ear a little bit.
Yeah,
I'm just thinking through how would you
do the quarterly inspection cadence with
service appointments? Like...
It seems like it would be an ongoing
service appointment and guys would log
into and keep updating as they go for an
entire month or maybe for a whole week or
something like that.
Like maybe week service appointments.
Yeah.
I mean, essentially at Victoria Gardens,
we would have 1125 service appointments,
but it's not on a weekly or monthly basis.
It's quarterly.
So, I don't...
Yeah,
would you really would you want an essay
per or?
Now, I would.
Would, yeah, it would,
it seems like maybe you could break it up
by sections.
Yeah, probably sections or, or uh,
or we got, I don't know, I...
You know, so if you did weekly,
that would definitely keep the guys on a
cadence,
make sure they're completing what they
should.
Um...
One of the things that came up was...
We sent out these reports and it's super
nice, but property managers like, hey,
you guys only did 10 inspections last
month or last week. I want a credit.
And I told Melissa, I said, Melissa,
you know,
So, wow.
we're doing quarterly inspections, like,
you know, because of, you know,
inclement weather or freeze or the water
was off, like.
Let's true up every quarter,
and if there's a credit owed,
we have no problem doing that. But,
you know,
a weekly credit or plus or minus is just
not, you know, feasible. So the point is,
the team's like, oh ****,
I need to track my cadence.
So if you had a weekly...
Cadence,
the guys would at least know that, okay,
I need to receive this.
Did I do what I'm supposed to do?
Here's my reminder.
Ki.
Yeah,
the questions around FSM aren't really.
Let's see.
How would you handle non-BV Connect
customers?
Mm.
Like,
are you showing these to the actual
residents too? Like the house?
Do they get,
do they see the inspection that this is
property manager level?
No.
No, it's property manager. Now the.
Okay, okay, good. Good, good.
N.
Oh,
can pull the inspection and show the
resident.
Okay.
And that was that was an ask by Melissa
Glenn to be able to do that.
So that's why kind of formatted a little
bit with a cover letter and all that
other jazz,
but it's not meant to be delivered to the
resident.
That someone did bring that up at some
point.
And, you know, I don't know,
I don't know how you would do that.
I mean,
if it was like Bright View Connect,
how could you,
is it on the roadmap to be able to
distribute?
And inspect through that.
No, not right now.
Yeah, I didn't think so, so...
Just asking.
It makes my stomach hurt to ask, but...
Yeah.
Hey, you know what?
So I did have a large property management
On.
company with Leland.
I think we talked about it once before
for Royal Palm.
There's residents that don't want to
register.
Is it on the roadmap anytime soon?
for them to be able to create service
requests without registering.
And.
No.
Okay. All right. And that's fine.
That's fine. I just, you know,
I wanted to ask because I know she's
going to bring it up again. So.
We have talked about that.
There is some backlog items surrounding,
I mean,
definitely the whole registration process
and how that happens.
Part of that has been a fire and forget
kind of idea, meaning
Mhm.
they can submit a service request without
being a registered user.
Mhm.
There's a lot of questions around that
and how they would actually get entry
into that and how would we verify that
they were an actual person.
for an actual resident of that community.
But I mean,
those are the main blockers to that kind
of solution.
It.
And it's down the backlog, right, but it,
but it is, but it is there.
Oh, that's fine.
Oh.
Mm.
And.
Let me see, and...
I think,
would Kelsie be willing to do a pilot?
What?
And...
So the, like Kelsie is,
we've actually minimized his book of
business because last week,
because we realized he's becoming
Yeah.
overwhelmed.
He's really good at what he does.
Yeah, I bet.
I think the branch would say,
I don't know, maybe.
Okay.
Maybe not.
If it has something to do with irrigation,
I think Andrew McCall would be the right
guy.
He's kind of holding the keys to the
coffer. Ultimately,
You.
he's the guy that Scott Sikora is looking
to to send out the weekly updates instead
Ohh, I'm scared. I don't think.
of me.
Because I make.
Yes, I agree.
So I think Andrew would definitely be
willing to be a part of that.
Oh.
Ney.
It.
Hang on a second.
Andrew McCall.
I have.
Yeah.
OK.
Okay.
I think.
Thank you.
But.
Okay. I think, I mean, Jay,
do you have any other thoughts or
questions around this?
Uh, no, I don't. Good.
Mike, have you ever looked at...
Any other solutions like that are based
on mapping,
so where you have an irrigation system
actually mapped out and...
Yeah.
You're laughing.
Yeah, I mean, I, man, I'm such a,
I love that ****, man. I just,
I don't have the bandwidth for it,
but this is,
this is the solution that I did for
mapping.
I know irrigation's got a lot of things
going on, but this is kind of,
These are all the jobs that, one,
we either maintain from targeting.
within the branch.
When I showed you that app when you were
down in Randall a few years back,
it was basically based off of this, that,
Yeah.
you know, the direction,
all that other stuff. But no, I,
Okay.
I've seen some.
I've seen some mapping available for
irrigation zones and things of that sort,
but I just haven't been able to dig into
it.
Okay.
All right, man,
I know you got a hard stop. Um, if I have.
.. well...
Can you,
is Victoria Gardens the only one using
this or how many properties are on this?
Yeah, so Victoria Gardens, right?
We keep talking about spreading it out
because it's a lot more user-friendly.
You can actually create irrigation
schedules within iAuditor.
We think that Andrew is the right guy to
be able to create a normal schedule, but..
.
OK.
Victoria Gardens, the only job today.
Okay.
Yep.
Alright, good deal.
We will hook up with Andrew.
Okay.
Michael, thank you so much.
If I have any more questions as we go
forward. And just so you know,
the thing that we're working on now,
we do have,
we got eight folks that are active in the
irrigation role that are part of our team
developing this.
And...
It is a,
it will be a form inside Field Service
Management.
Mhm.
And...
As we get closer,
I'll share the progress with you as well,
just so you can see what we're what we're
what we're getting to.
Ki.
Okay.
Our goal is July to have this out in
pilot.
But I'll work with Andrew to see.
who he thinks would be good to pilot
something.
And I think we'll add him to our to our
stack of folks,
potentially need to talk to him first,
but is he like a...
Okay.
Like market-wide or region-wide
irrigation or. OK. OK.
So no, he's branch, he's branch. Yeah,
I mean, it's,
I think you guys are definitely doing the
right thing. When you look up the ladder,
there's not a whole lot of senior
leadership that's irrigation related and
it's such a big part of our business.
Yeah.
Um, yeah, you just,
but he's just in the Sanford territory.
How about, do you know Edwin Gonzalez?
I do know Edwin. Yes. Yeah.
Is he, in your opinion,
is he a good candidate to help us?
He, he is.
I don't know if he's as technically savvy
as Andrew,
but he knows he knows his business for
That's good. I mean,
I'd rather have some non-tech people.
sure.
Yeah, so, so it would be good,
it would be good for sure.
Okay. How about Carlos Victoria?
That guy is, yeah,
he's he's forgotten more than most people
know regarding your he.
Okay, so he's a seasoned irrigation guy.
Is Carlos considered that guy?
Okay.
Yeah, yeah.
Awesome.
Those are the two, they are on our team.
Perfect. Yeah. Yeah.
Okay.
Okay, good. Good to know.
Alright, awesome. Well,
if you have any questions too, man,
you know, you know where to find me.
Yeah, for sure, man. I appreciate it.
Alright, Jay, you got anything else?
Nope, I'm good. Thanks, Michael.
Alright, thanks guys.
Bye, guys. Thank you.
Thea.
All right, bye.
But...
Right.